Venus Ang

Lead Senior Front-End Software Engineer San Diego • venusang24@gmail.com

WEBSITE

LINKEDIN

GITHUB

http://www.missdemilo.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/venusang

http://github.com/venusang

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Lead Senior Front-End Software Engineer with 10+ years experience developing Enterprise software applications. Proven track record of delivering user experiences that are delightful and attractive. Committed to contributing to a positive work environment while guiding team success and growth.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

LEAD SENIOR FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Mar 2020 - Present

HashiCorp Cloud Platform (HCP) - Team Cloud Identity Enterprise, Remote

- Code in HTML, CSS and JavaScript within Ember.js framework
- Helped developed new <u>HashiCorp Cloud Platform (HCP)</u> from the ground up in March 2020 on a team of 3 front-end engineers public beta was released in October 2020
- Develop reusable front-end components based on designs and best practices, including accessibility
- Contribute to HashiCorp's design system of reusable components <u>Helios Design System</u>
- Conduct code reviews
- Write integration and acceptance tests to ensure reliability
- Troubleshoot and fix software bugs
- Communicate and collaborate with design and product on a regular basis
- Present demos and lead knowledge sharing sessions
- Plan, execute and communicate internally the release of new HCP features
- Develop software tooling packages to improve engineer productivity
- Contribute to the planning of technical roadmap initiatives
- Lead software operational excellence to enhance system efficiency and reliability
- Foster a positive team environment to enhance project turnaround time
- Lead a collaborative team of 3 front-end software engineers
- Mentor and train junior engineers
- Collaborate with a team of 10 backend engineers
- Lead the execution of technical roadmap initiatives
- Project plan to meet initiatives and estimate engineering level of effort using JIRA and Agile (SCRUM) methodologies
- Streamline team processes to accelerate software deployment
- Cross-collaborate with other teams within HashiCorp to build a community, achieve project goals
- Author technical documentation, including Request for Comments (RFC's) and Architectural Requirement Documents (ADR's) to communicate and promote technical decisions and ideas to engineers, designers and product managers
- Interview potential software frontend engineer candidates
- Helped company grow from 900 employees to 2000+
- Promoted to Lead Senior Engineer II in March 2023
- Promoted to Senior Software Engineer II May 2022 March 2023
- Hired as Senior Software Engineer March 2020 May 2022

TBWA/Media Arts Lab, Marina Del Rey, CA

- Architected and designed UI and UX for internal asset management software application Maintained and developed existing internal business software application used for project management
- Engineered robust full-stack solutions
- Optimized code for enhanced system performance
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects
- Resolved complex technical issues with innovative solutions
- Enforced code standards to ensure quality and maintainability

SENIOR FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2015 - Nov 2018

Cofense (Formerly PhishMe), Remote

- Developed innovative software solutions
- Fostered team unity
- Refined software products based on Stakeholder feedback
- Developed reusable components
- Recommended UI solutions
- Pair-programmed with colleagues
- Documented front-end development best practices
- Planned and executed project activities using JIRA and Slack
- Worked 100% remote in start-up environment
- Helped company grow from 100 to 600+ employees
- Conducted software engineer candidate interviews

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Including but not limited to: infosec, entertainment, e-commerce solutions, financial, health and fitness. Worked full-time as a software front-end developer with Walt Disney Studios, Creative Artists Agency (CAA), Disney Interactive Media Group (DIMG), Fox Interactive Media Group (MySpace), Kaiser Permanente, Universal Online

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ASSOCIATE INSTRUCTOR

Feb 2022 - Aug 2023

ThriveDX, remote

SINGLE-SUBJECT SECONDARY MATHEMATICS TEACHER

Oct 2001 - Oct 2004

Hale Middle School (LAUSD), Woodland Hills

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Instructional Technology

National University, San Diego, CA Graduated with honors

Clear Single-Subject Credential in Secondary Mathematics

National University, San Diego, CA

Bachelor of Science in Engineering

Cal Poly State University, San Luis Obispo, CA

SKILLS

HTML, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, Front-end Frameworks (Ember, Vue, React. Angular), Qunit, Mocha, Chai, Playwright, Responsive Web, API Integration, LaunchDarkly, Full-Stack Development, Go, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, JAVA, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Project planning with JIRA, Scrum, Agile, Autho, AWS, Azure, Terraform, Photoshop, Illustrator, UI/UX Design, Figma, Sketch, Balsamiq, Storybook, Mirage, Datadog, Vercel, VS Code